The patriot, the professor, the comic and the stripper... were
fighting for what they believed in... Getting rich!
Escape to Athena is a adventure, comedy, war film
directed by George P. Cosmatos.
During the World War II, the prisoners of a German camp
in a Greek island are trying to escape.
They not only want their freedom, but also seek an ineffable treasure
hidden in a monastery at the summit of the island's mountain.
Otto Hecht, played by Roger Moore.
Zeno, played by Telly Savalas.
Professor Blake, played by David Niven.
Dottie Del Mar, played by Stefanie Powers.
Eleana, played by Claudia Cardinale.
Nat Judson, played by Richard Roundtree.
Escape to Athena is a 1979 British adventure
comedy war film directed by George P.
It stars Roger Moore, Telly Savalas, David Niven, Stefanie Powers, Claudia
Cardinale, Richard Roundtree, Sonny Bono and Elliott Gould.
The film is set during the Second World War on a German-occupied Greek island.
The music was composed by Lalo Schifrin.
It was filmed on location on the island of Rhodes.
The film explores themes of island, escape, world
war ii, prisoner of war, greece.
The tone is lighthearted.